Real quick before we jump into design techniques,
在真正进入到可视化设计部分之前
it's important to discuss the purpose of visualizations.
我们有必要来谈论一下数据可视化的目的
Visualizations can be used for two main purposes when analyzing
分析数据时 可视化主要有两个目的
data Exploratory analysis and Explanatory analysis.
即探索性分析与解释性分析
Exploratory analysis is done behind the scenes.
探索性分析属于幕后工作
This is the type of analysis where you're searching for
主要用来寻找数据里的变量间关系
relationships in the data or hidden insights.
或者隐藏的见解
Once you've collected the data,
一旦收集了数据
you can start asking questions about it.
你就可以着手提出有关数据的问题
The way you analyze data to try and answer these questions is known as exploratory.
分析并尝试回答这些问题的过程就是探索
Visualizations built for these purposes,
为探索性目的创建的可视化
do not need to be perfect.
并不需要完美
You're simply looking for patterns.
你只是想找到一些模式
Explanatory analysis is done after you find an insight.
解释性分析 则是在你得出结论之后进行的
Visualizations for these purposes need to be surrounded by
为此目的创建的可视化需要采用讲故事的形式
a story that points the reader to an insight that answers the question.
把你发现的结论展现给读者
Many times these explanatory visuals were found during the exploratory process.
很多时候 解释性的可视化是在探索过程中被发现的
But rather than share every step and piece of data that led to this
但是 你不需要分享探索性分析中的每一个细节
visualization,you ask the question and then
你要做的是提出问题
focus on answering the question with a visualization that supports your finding.
然后专注于如何用图表把你发现的问题答案展现出来
There are five steps in the data analysis process.
数据分析过程包括五个步骤
First, you extract your data.
首先 提取数据
You might get the data from a survey,
你的数据可能来自于问卷调查
a database, the web or some other source.
数据库、网络或其他数据源
Then you can clean the data.
然后 清洗数据
As a part of this process,
这一步可能包含
you might fix missing values,
处理缺失值、
determine which columns to keep, round values,
确定要保留的数据列、对数据进行四舍五入
or perform some other tricks to get the data in a way that you can analyze it.
或者其他的数据处理方法 最终得到能够用来分析的数据
The next step is exploring your data.
再下一步是探索数据
The visuals used for cleaning, exploring,
用于数据清洗、探索与分析的可视化
and analyzing your data are part of the exploratory data analysis process.
属于探索性数据分析过程的一部分
The visuals created here and even during
在这些阶段 (包括数据清洗步骤) 中创建的可视化
the cleaning phase don't need to be super pretty or super clear in their message.
并不需要特别漂亮或者让人一目了然
They're just for you, the analyst to determine what is going on in the data.
它们只是你作为分析师用来挖掘数据的手段
Once you explore the data,
一旦完成了数据的探索
you might determine a particular analysis that was best to answer a particular question.
你可能确定某种特定的分析方法 来最恰当地回答某个特定的问题
Maybe you are predicting sales,
比如预测销售额、
or fraud, or home prices,
欺诈或房价
when you find an insight to share the visuals used
一旦得出了值得分享的见解
for sharing this insight or part of the explanatory visuals.
用于分享结论的可视化就属于解释性分析的一部分
These visuals tell the story of the finding and what it means.
这些可视化讲述的是数据中包含的故事及其意义
They motivate the actions and move your audience forward.
它们能够为你的听众带来某些价值 改变或者促进某些行为
The role of this lesson is to build visuals that will be used for explanatory analysis.
本课的最终目的 就是创建可用于解释性分析的可视化